ADAMU M. DANKORE

Charles City, Iowa 50616 || (319) 296-5799 adamu.dankore@gmail.com || https://www.dankore.com

SUMMARY

An experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in JavaScript, React, Ruby, MongoDB, Express, Node, marketing and launching startups. Strong engineering and design professional with over 12 million impressions of design work on Facebook.

TOOL STACKS / COMPETENCIES

JavaScript • Node.js • React • Express • Ruby • MongoDB • Front-End Web Development • Back-End Web Development • Data Structures • Bootstrap • Tailwind CSS • HTML5 • CSS3 • NoSQL • Object Oriented Programming • GitHub • Gitlab • Marketing • Design • Social Media Marketing • Version Control • Problem Solving • Client/Server Side • Ajax • Management • MVC Architecture • Databases • Slack • Troubleshooting • JSON • REST API • Modern Web Security • GIT • SEO • Teamwork • SAP • JSX • SPA • SQL • Access • VBA

EXPERIENCE

HOME AWAY FROM HOME

Software Engineer & Head of Marketing

Remote, Part-Time November 2018 - Present

- Lead a small marketing team which grew the startup to 4,000 unique visits and 400,000 SSL requests a month
- Wrote Hyperapp code running in a Docker Swam cluster
- Increased brand visibility through product design, targeted marketing, and content addition
- Designed and implemented views using Tailwind CSS

CAMBREX

Process Support Chemist

Charles City, Iowa November 2017 – Present

- Our site saved the company more than Seven Million U.S. Dollars since 2017 to date
- Perform chemical testing on a variety of pharmaceutical grade instrument such as HPLC, GC, NMR, and FTIR
- One of my technical suggestions is been used by our lab manager to facilitate effective and money-saving communication
- Working in one of the most regulated industries in the world that enforce strict compliance to EP, DEA, and FDA
 regulations

FREELANCE

Full Stack Web Developer and Designer

January 2018 - Present

- Designed and developed custom websites for clients based on specifications
- Gained over 12 million impressions and 230k shares of graphic design work on Facebook
- Collaborated and worked iteratively with clients to determine the necessary project requirements

PROJECTS

GSS GWARINPA NETWORK | http://www.gssgwarinpa.com

- Developed a social networking app for current and past students of my former secondary school
- Implemented modern web security features to protect users' personal data
- The site has been receiving positive feedback from students and alumni and continues to grow day-by-day

MS ACCESS DATABASE PROJECTS | Internal Company Applications

- Developing an app that would utilize the company's analytical tests database to send uniform end-of-shift email report
- Developing a user-driven project-based MS Access database that would allow chemists to sign up for volunteer projects
- Both projects are expected to boost productivity and communication amongst laboratory personnel

EDUCATION

B.A in Chemistry & Minor in Leadership

Wartburg College, Waverly, Iowa Honors: Dean's list

CERTIFICATIONS / TECHNICAL EDUCATION

App Academy's Intro to Ruby • FreeCodeCamp's Responsive Web Design • SoloLearn's JavaScript Course • Adult First Aid/CPR/AED • MongoDB Essentials - Understand the Basics of MongoDB (Udemy) • VSchool's Learn React: A Comprehensive Introduction